Walnut Creek, CA (408) 242-0789 rao.shantanu@amail.com

Shantanu Rao

shanrao.org github.com/qwertyshan linkedin.com/in/shanrao

Summary

- Highly rated product leader with multiple, successful product launches
- Award winning technologist with experiences spanning the full product development cycle

Relevant Skills

Product: Strategy, User Research, Analytics, A/B Tests, Design Thinking, Agile

Mobile and Web: iOS, Swift, Python, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript Cloud and Data: Linux, SQL, Hadoop, Google Cloud, AWS

Networks and Security: TCP/IP stack, HTTP, SSL, DNS, cybersecurity, cryptography

Work Experience

Product Manager, Services Products

November 2013 – March 2015

Palo Alto Networks, Santa Clara, CA

- Product-managed the complete technical services product line (\$200M annual revenue).
- Conducted user interviews and data analyses to understand latent customer needs.
- Led cross-functional teams comprising engineering, sales, marketing, and services with an empathetic leadership style.
- Facilitated executive level strategy sessions and decisions, both internally and with customers.
- Created business cases, product roadmaps, product requirements, wireframes, mockups, marketing collateral, and pricing proposals.
- Launched four successful products with exclusive ownership from concept to launch.
- Awarded top quarterly honor (June 2014) in a 20-member product management organization.

Manager, Technical Support Engineering

April 2011 – November 2013

Brocade, San Jose, CA

- Managed a highly-successful engineering team (of 16) responsible for all technical services (\$12M annual revenue) for Brocade's application delivery product line.
- Rated "Top Performer" (3 times in 2011-2013) for delivering highest customer satisfaction by any team in the product division.
- Provided technical expertise on design and operation of high-performance, customer-facing application infrastructures.
- Led executive-level sales and services discussions with clients such as Yahoo, AT&T, Rackspace, and Goldman Sachs.

Senior Product Engineer, Application Delivery

July 2008 – April 2011

Brocade, San Jose, CA

- Engineered complex systems to solve data-center problems related to: server load balancing, network application optimization, DNS-based global traffic distribution, web-caching, and high-availability/redundancy of network appliances.
- Designed and developed a highly-regarded lab management application (PHP and MySQL). It is still used by many Brocade engineers who prefer it over Brocade's "official" lab application.
- Rated "Top Performer" (2010) for strong technical results.

Network Security Engineer

July 2007 - July 2008

Cisco, San Jose, CA

- Provided advanced technical consulting to Cisco customers on firewalls, VPN, Intrusion Prevention Systems (IPS), security management software, and enterprise routing and switching.
- Achieved CCNA and CCIE Security (written) certifications.

Graduate Researcher

August 2005 – June 2007

Wichita State University, Wichita, KS

- Designed a secure architecture for the management of consumer mobile RFID devices.
 Publication: soar.wichita.edu/handle/10057/1528
- Developed proof-of-concept simulation software in C++.
- Researched performance characteristics of video and audio encoding algorithms over IP networks.

Independent Coursework

- Product Design
- Rapid Prototyping
- Human Centered Design
- Innovation: Ideas to Marketplace

- Full Stack Foundations
- Developing Scalable Apps in Python
- OAuth: Authentication & Authorization
- Managing an Agile Team

Education

Nanodegree, iOS Software Development, Udacity

February 2016

M.S. Electrical Engineering, Wichita State University

May 2007

- Graduated top of class
- Chapter President of Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

B.S. Computer Engineering, Wichita State University

May 2005

- Maana cum Laude
- Awarded university's most prestigious leadership honor (Senior Honor Man)